Guide to the Pittsburgh Peace Institute Records, 1984-1997 AIS.1998.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Education and Outreach, 1984-1997; II.
  - Making Choices Schools, Frick International Studies Academy, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Making Choices Schools, Good Samaritan Catholic, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Making Choices Schools, Greenway Middle School, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Making Choices Schools, The Health Place, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Making Choices Schools, Mon Valley Educational Consortium, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Making Choices Schools, Mt. Oliver Intermediate Unit #2, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Making Choices Schools, Ozanam Center, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Making Choices Schools, Quaker Valley Middle School, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Making Choices Schools, Reizenstein General Information, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Making Choices Schools, Reizenstein Proposal, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Making Choices Schools, Reizenstein Assessments, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Making Choices Schools, Reizenstein Funding Letter, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Making Choices Schools, Reizenstein Middle School, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Making Choices Schools, Reizenstein Crime Watch, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Making Choices Schools, Schiller Classical Academy, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Making Choices Schools, Seneca Valley Middle School, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Making Choices Schools, Serra Catholic High School, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Making Choices Schools, South Park High School, 1993-1997 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Making Choices Schools, St. Edmunds Academy, 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Making Choices Schools, St. Sylvester School, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Making Choices Schools, Tilloston School, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Making Choices Schools, Veteran's For Peace, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Making Choices Schools, West Jefferson Hills School District, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Making Choices Schools, Winchester Thurston, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Making Choices Schools, Woodland Hills School District, 1993-1997 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Making Choices Schools, Worely, Virginia After School Music Program, undated (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Making The Future, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Multicultural Awareness Workshop, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Multicultural Education Outline, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Nonviolence: Sharing the Vision, Changing the World, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Nonviolence Statement, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Nonviolent Problem Solving Workshop, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Nonviolent Problem Solving Session at the "A Celebration of Women" Conference, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Peaceful Civil Disobedience Outline, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Peace Educator, The Peace Lady, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The Peace Educator, 1992-1997 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - The Peace Educator, vol.1, no.1, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Peace Educator, vol. 2, no. 1, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Peace Educator, vol. 2, no. 2, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Peace Educator, vol. 2, no. 3, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - The Peace Educator, vol. 2, no. 4, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Peace Festival in North Park, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Peace Movement and Peace Education Conference, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Peaceful Person, Peaceful Planet Materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Persian Gulf War Materials, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Peace and Justice Week Citation for Pittsburgh, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Pittsburgh Association of School Social Work Personnel Conference, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Pittsburgh Educators Meeting, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Roots of Prejudice planning, 1993-1998 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - School Violence Prevention Seminar, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - The Simpleton Story, by. Liane Ellison Norman, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Star Wars: Waking up from the Dream, by. Marie Norman and Caitie McQuade, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Stories to Live By program, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - The Subject is Nonviolence, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - The Subject is Nonviolence, Fall 1993 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - The Subject is Nonviolence, Summer 1993 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - The Subject is Nonviolence, Fall 1994 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - The Subject is Nonviolence, Spring 1994 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - The Subject is Nonviolence, Winter 1995 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Teacher-Artz, Nancy J., undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Teacher Training Evaluations, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Thank You Letters, 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - University of Pittsburgh "Peace Education in Secondary Schools" Panel, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Violent Impacts Conference, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Violence Prevention Workshop Brochures, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Violence Prevention Packet, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Violence Prevention Bibliography, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Women and The Americans Program, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Youth Violence and Violence Prevention Workshop, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Youth Violence and Violence Prevention Teacher Training, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Audio and Visual Materials, 1992-1997; III.
  This series dates from 1992-1997 and includes photographs of meeting, panels, and classroom pilot projects, as well as VHS tapes of a pilot Making Choices class and documentary of the underground railroad in Pittsburgh, which features interviews with PPI's John Burt.
  - Photographs
    - Dr. Seuss Pilot Project at East Liberty Presbyterian Church, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Workshop at First Baptist Church, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Panel Discussion at the Presbyterian Church of Plum Creek, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Making Choices Pilot at Reizenstein Middle School, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Dr. Seuss Pilot at Evergreen Elementary, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Abolitionist Tour, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Holiday Food Preparation, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Making Choices Teacher Training, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Unknown Demonstration in Downtown Pittsburgh, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Video
    - Making Choices Pilot Program at Reizenstein Middle School, 1992 (Box 5, Video 54)
    - WPXI Special, Pennsylvania's Pathways to Freedom, featuring interviews with PPI's John Burt, 1997 (Box 5, Video 55)